Good morning. It's Wednesday, March
11th. Thank you for tuning in to the
program with Ted Rall and John Kiriakou.
Good morning, John. Good morning, Ted.
Uh so, by the way, my voice was accused
of being squeaky by one of the
commenters yesterday. And so, I
apologize.
>> [laughter]
>> I was I was doing a covert action video
once.
The CIA and I almost walked out
when um the big boss came in and said
that my eyes were too squinty.
>> [laughter]
>> Is that a racist comment?
Yeah, seriously. Why I oughta
>> [laughter]
>> Well, I mean, I don't know. Maybe my
voice is squeaky. I don't know. We'll
let the We'll let the people decide. Um
so, just as we went on the air, the news
is coming out of the Strait of feeding
into our main story this morning. Strait
of Hormuz is the main is the main focus
of the war now. Iran just hit three
vessels. We don't know what kind. We
don't know who they belong to.
>> We do know. Two two bulk tankers and a
cargo ship. Do we know who they're
flagged to? Not yet, but one was hit
in Omani waters and two in Emirati
waters.
And also, the other big breaking news is
the new inflation numbers are out. No
big deal. I don't think we're going to
see the effect of the war yet cuz the
war hadn't begun. This is for the month
of February.
Inflation for February is which
obviously was before the war is a steady
at about 2.4%. Not usually a very bad
number, but gas prices were already
rising.
By the way, I checked the markets right
before we went on the air, John. Oil
price oil futures are bouncing back up
early today. And also, looks like it's
going to be a down day, not a crash on
the stock on the stock exchanges. We'll
see.
So, the
basically, it looks like the insiders in
the administration, the smart ones, are
calling the Strait of Hormuz their Death
Valley, thus the name of today's
episode. They're saying it's basically a
no-win situation where basically all the
ships are either stuck or as Trump
suggests they grow some balls and try to
run the straight. Why would they do
that? Their bosses won't let them. And
or the US Navy has to go in there and
risk its own assets. It's a no-win
situation.
The CNN, although this is not a very
reliable report, claims that Iran has
already begun laying mines in the Strait
of Hormuz.
Um
The US says it's destroyed
a bunch about a dozen or more mine
layers, but the Iranians still have a
lot of ability with small boats and mine
layers. So it could feasibly lay
hundreds of mines.
And commercial and a basically it's an
economic war now, John. It's drones are
hitting Dubai International Airport, the
world's busiest international airport.
The joint military command in Iran now
says it's going to start targeting banks
and financial institutions in the Middle
East. We're also going to talk about a
domestic story later in the show.
BART, which is the iconic mass transit
system for San Francisco, looks like
it's entered a death spiral. It may
actually be forced to close, which is
>> How nuts is that? It's nuts. I mean it
was
>> is Yeah, it's like one of the wealthiest
cities Yeah, exactly. One of the
wealthiest cities in America.
$2 billion a day for war, but we don't
have $400 million a year for BART.
It's insane. This is nuts. Strait of
Hormuz, shall we? Yeah.
Okay.
Well, so
>> say you can't say you're shocked cuz the
Iranians have been warning everybody for
weeks now
stop [__] with us or we're going to
close the Strait of Hormuz and just
paralyze the global economy.
And yet it does look like some people
were surprised and they're the planners
inside the administration. I mean the
New York Times and the Washington Post
are reporting today that uh you know,
they're kind of surprised that the
Iranians are are being so spicy this
time. John, if you
you you you know, you you've been in the
in you know, at the agency. Isn't it
like normal to look at your adversary
you know, at conflicts from your
adversary's point of view? And like from
the from the Iranians' point of view,
right? I mean, they've already they know
that this will keep happening, right?
Like especially with the Israelis
involved. John, tell me if I'm wrong and
then I'll just throw it to you.
>> No, no, you're my percent right. In
fact, the job of the analyst is to ask
what if
and then
come up with with the analysis. That's
your job. Your job is supposed to always
always have a paper ready to go. What if
Iran closes the Strait of Hormuz? Iran
blows up another American embassy? You
know, something that that can just be
pulled right off the shelf.
I mean, it looks to me like so with the
Iranians on board, right? We're kind of
share they're you know, whenever you
have a partner, you always risk making
their mistakes that you wouldn't have
made yourself. Yeah. The the Israeli
approach to Gaza for years has been this
horrible term like mowing the lawn,
right? Like go in every few years and
bomb the crap out of stuff to degrade
Hamas and their ability to function
properly effectively.
I [snorts] think that's kind of what
they had in mind for Iran and they did
that, you know, already twice
um you know, with the assassination of
Soleimani uh and now and then last year
with the uh 12-day war. And I think they
were just thinking, we'll go in every
now and then and do this. But the
Iranians are like
we can't have that. We can't live that
way. We're not going to allow that. Um
killed our supreme leader. We our
domestic domestically our politics won't
tolerate it. We're just This is
existential for them. Why didn't That's
obvious to me. Why would wouldn't it be
obvious?
>> Clear.
Crystal clear, Ted. I don't get it,
either.
You Well, you know what? I I retract
that. I I get it. I'm sure that the
analysis is still being done, whether
it's at CIA or DIA or the Pentagon or
wherever.
I think that the White House is just
ignoring it. They made a policy
decision. It was not based on the
analysis or the intelligence. That's
usual. And they're just going with their
policy decision.
And but I mean And so basically what
we're reading now is that uh in terms of
the economic war, oil prices are you
know, they're expecting a bounce, but
they think that as long as things start
to settle down within a month,
uh that basically they'll be okay and
they'll be able to ride things through
to the midterm elections, which by the
way are already not looking good for
them.
Is that I mean, how I don't know how
realistic that is. And also, don't
Iranians read newspapers, too? Yeah,
exactly. Can't they just be like, "Oh,
well, we just have to hold on." To to
give you an idea of the of the political
situation for Republicans right now,
too,
we didn't have a chance yesterday to
talk about this, but a Republican
congressman from California
quit the Republican Party yesterday.
Mhm. He said he'll he'll continue to
caucus with Republicans for the rest of
the year, but he is now a registered
independent. He is no longer a
Republican member of Congress. He blamed
redistricting.
>> a huge deal. Now, every once in a while
a Democrat will do that. They'll switch
to the Republicans.
It's highly unusual for a Republican to
quit the Republican Party.
That's true.
And what do I mean, do you make that
like I mean, he blamed redistricting. Do
you think that's right, or do you think
it's just like this a guy This guy knows
how to read polls? In part, and in part
I think that he's thinking, "What is
happening at the White House? Why are
they not listening to anybody who has to
face reelection?"
And I'm just seeing that that we just
bombed the Armenian corridor.
Uh sorry quarter in in Tehran. Why in
the world would we do that?
Well, the reports have been like um you
know of I'm glad you brought that up
John cuz the you know the the reports of
civilian damage in infrastructure in
Tehran are coming in in a scattered way
because the internet's down, right? And
it's The Iranians I I've been there
somewhere in my photos I have like a
screenshot of like you know being in
Iran when it was like you can't access
this website, right? And it's like in in
Farsi. So they do that in times like
this cuz they don't want to be hacked.
They don't want another Stuxnet virus or
anything like that. But also they're
they're sort of putting the kibosh on
the Israeli spies who are there and you
know basically but also
you know it may have been bombed. Some
of the infrastructure may have just been
bombed. But it sounds like a lot of the
reports even in the New York Times which
are not normally very flowery say that
the that Tehran is really being very
screwed up
and that the people are living in a
state of total terror. You know I heard
yesterday that much of the bombing in
Tehran is in residential areas which the
Israelis do all the time. All you have
to do is look at Beirut and the the
southern Beirut suburbs.
Um
the only purpose to bombing civilian
areas is to kill people.
That's it. There there's no military
reason why you would bomb civilian
targets other than to kill as many human
beings as possible.
And it seems they're going to kill 92
million Iranians, right? So so like they
I mean
>> can frighten 92 million Iranians. Yeah,
but isn't that just basically isn't that
kind of a total war approach? Just going
to push Iranians closer to the govern to
their government you know which by the
way wasn't that popular going into all
this.
>> No, but people rally around their
governments even when they're unpopular
when they feel attacked as a whole. Look
at 9/11 and George W. Bush's 90%
approval rating after 9/11. People rally
to their leaders. Eight months after Oh,
sorry, nine months after Bush v. Gore,
you know, I remember the polls showed
that like 48% of Americans didn't even
think Bush was the legitimate president
of the United States in early 2001.
That's right. 91% approval just like
that.
Um
and that's you know, and frankly 9/11
was nothing compared to uh you know, the
kind of attack that Tehran is is
suffering right now, you know, night
after night after night, day after day.
>> Yeah. With Yeah, with two heavily armed
military forces after Why do the
Iranians want to kill civilians? I mean,
what what's their thinking there?
The Iranians or these races?
>> sorry, sorry, the Israelis. Yeah, the
Israelis I you know, I think that it's
God.
This is something I'll tell myself in my
head I've never vocalized before. I
think that the Israelis so hate Muslims
that they just want to kill as many as
possible. You know, I say all the time,
the reason we saw dancing Israelis in
the streets of New York after 9/11 is
because they knew what this attack on
the World Trade Center meant. They meant
they knew that it meant that the United
States would go to war and would kill as
many Muslims as possible. And then over
the next 25 years, we killed 2 million
Muslims.
And so, I think that they do the same
thing.
I mean, it's if true, it's I don't
really
I just don't see how that serves Israeli
national interests, but
>> I agree. I agree. I think it's
I think it's counter to Israeli
interests. Um let's
producer Robbie West has some
housekeeping to uh conduct. So, Robbie,
take it away. Yep. Uh this will be real
quick. I was going to schedule some
streams for John over on his Rumble
channel yesterday. Things happened. I
was not able to do it. I will instead be
doubling up today. So you're going to
get triple amounts of John Kiriakou if
you're following him on his official
Rumble channel.
Also, the great Ted Rall fitting sitting
quite your properly to my far left will
get be getting more animated cartoons up
on his X account today. So if you enjoy
that stuff, keep an eye out and that's
all I got. Goodbye. Thank you Robbie for
the awesome animations. Robbie, do we
have an ad?
Uh sure, I can do that for you. Yeah,
throw that. Thank you.
Um okay, so John, we have a question
that came in overnight and this one is
for you.
It's from a Nasse Gupta.
Uh did John ever have correspondence
with Christopher Hitchens? Was he aware
of his Vanity Fair piece where he
experienced waterboarding firsthand to
try to see if it really was as cruel and
inhumane as it was portrayed? I'd love
to know your thought John's thoughts on
on Chris as he and John are two people I
admire and respect a lot.
Thank you for that question. Nobody's
ever asked me that before. Um yeah, I
was in touch with Christopher Hitchens.
He we talked about waterboarding and
what it felt like. He thought that I was
exaggerating and so he did it and
I wasn't exaggerating.
It was as bad as I told him it was going
to be.
Uh I I had great admiration for Chris
Hitchens. Brilliant writer,
dedicated analyst, deep thinker,
um
renowned atheist.
And I think that his premature death was
was bad for journalism.
Yeah. I saw his I saw the video. You can
it's probably kicking around on YouTube
or something.
Um
it was
I heard that he was PTSD'd. He never
really got over the fake waterboarding.
Crazy. Um I I have to admit I was I was
pissed off at Christopher Hitchens
because he supported the invasion of
Iraq. Yeah, he did. And uh He later said
that he felt that he had been duped.
I think maybe duped by the bottom of a a
whiskey bottle, but that's just me. Um
he also made made sure that everybody
knew that you know, if
moments before his death, he suddenly
decided that God was real and you know,
he wanted to be baptized or something
that it was just the the chemical dump
in his brain talking and he didn't
really mean it. I hear he didn't do
that.
Yeah, that's what I heard, too. So well,
you know, good on him for that. You
know, I hate the last minute my my
in-laws who were lifelong not people of
faith decided at the last moment to to
convert and
you know, I was just like, that's kind
of cheating, but you know. Yeah. All
right, you probably noticed Rumble is
growing fast and it's not slowing down.
They're building a real alternative to
Big Tech that puts creators first and
actually protects free speech. And now
there's Rumble Premium, an easy way to
upgrade your experience. With Premium,
you get ad-free viewing across the
platform, no pre-rolls, no
interruptions, just the content you came
for. Plus Premium members unlock
exclusive content like bonus videos,
behind-the-scenes drops and more from
your favorite creators. Right now,
Rumble is offering 10 bucks off an
annual subscription. Just go to
rumble.com/premium and use the promo
code studio at checkout. That's
rumble.com/premium,
promo code studio. No ads, more freedom
and content you actually care about.
That's the deal. So
John, the the administration is
basically look it looks like they're
looking for an off-ramp
and it looks like they kind of like want
to be like, well, we're going to declare
victory and just and just say we're
done. But the Iranians get a vote here,
right? I mean
if
you're the Iranians, don't you just keep
going?
Absolutely.
Like we said what a week ago, Ted? Maybe
now it's a little bit more than a week
ago.
The for the Americans and the Israelis
to win, there has to be utter complete
regime change and not just regime
change, but a a new pro-American and
probably pro-Israeli regime needs to be
installed.
All the Iranians need to do to win is to
survive. That's it.
And they Oh, by the way, there's report
that
Khomeini Ayatollah Khomeini Jr. He He He
was injured in the attack that killed
his father.
Ooh. His legs were were hurt, but he's
generally okay.
>> [snorts]
>> Wow, right. Um so, yeah, no, I mean, all
the signs I see are of of defiance. By
the way, have you seen any of the
propaganda videos coming out from Iran?
Um
I wish you'd run some of them tomorrow.
Yeah. Um they're kind of amazing. So, a
lot of them are generated by AI. But, uh
there's a version of There's one video
that is reportedly released by the
Revolutionary Guards that has It's
basically set to the tune of These boots
are meant for walking by Nancy Sinatra.
And it shows like Iranian missiles, you
know, streaming towards Israel and
Netanyahu running. Um there's
a weird LEGO video where basically
it shows the bombing of the school and
like a
like a Quds Force or some like dude like
really angry and then like the the
revenge rains down on Israel. Um it's I
mean, the the cyber war is also a really
interesting aspect of this. I mean,
you know, do you think this is something
that like the CIA would have been
interested in you well, is interested in
now?
Yes.
Yes, definitely.
>> Propaganda. Yeah, propaganda. You know,
when I first started at the CIA, I
entered on duty EOD'd with um
with a guy.
He asked me what I was going to work on
and I said, "Oh, I'm going to leadership
analysis. How about you?" He said, "I'm
going to uh propaganda and covert
action." I said, "That sounds kind of
cool." Totally. And he's Yeah, and he
said He said, "Yeah,
I mean, there was still a Soviet Union."
As you I'm dating myself.
There was still a Soviet Union when I
got hired, so he was doing uh
anti-Soviet propaganda.
So, it's not not like not like it's
something new. I mean, they've they've
had groups at the CIA doing this and not
just against the Soviets for decades.
So, yeah, definitely it would be part of
the what what's called Persia House.
I hate that that term.
Why is it called that?
Oh, they thought it would be cute. Back
when I was still there, they they
created um
uh Russia House, then Iraq House, now
Persia House. I don't know. It's
silliness.
Uh okay. Um okay, so let's uh shall we
do some ads?
Sounds good. Okay. Uh first one we can
dispose of right away. Aaron Barca, John
needs a shirt that says pardon me.
I have one, actually. We have such a
shirt. Yeah, Trent sent it to me. And
you can buy one on uh you can buy one on
the um right, can't you? I think so.
Yeah, here on here on the website. Uh
there it is. I'll put it up. deep
deprogram.live. I'm pretty sure. If not,
if I'm mistaken, cuz I'm on the air, I
can't really look at it. Um
is it there?
Yep. Okay, cool. I'll leave that up
there. Uh okay. Uh Nards26,
always Does Does John believe his
Australian visa was denied for political
reasons?
Yes.
I don't want to believe that.
But yes, because I had already been
>> [clears throat]
>> to Australia.
Right? And I just applied for another
visa 2 years after my first trip there
and they said no, intending immigrant.
So, as soon as I said that publicly that
I'd been denied, several Australian um
immigration attorneys reached out to me
and said, "Happy to help. Won't charge
you anything." And I said I appreciate
it, but my little window that I had to
actually go to Australia had closed.
But, I I'll get back there
sooner or later. Thanks for the two
bucks from Hog. I quoted John in my
federal lawsuit. Uh Hog's Candyland and
>> Hey, great. the program. Uh thanks for
the five bucks also from Hog's. Uh there
are rules for every Oh, here's the
quote. There are rules for everything
that no one pays attention to. Nothing
works the way it's supposed to. John
Kiriakou. Uh
Bielaczyc, welcome to the show also on
YouTube. Thanks for the 29.99 Australian
bucks from uh Zizic. Uh not to not the
uh Slovenian philosopher. Ezra, thanks
for the five bucks. Super chat ignored
yesterday. We are sorry, sorry, sorry.
Trying again. We'll do better this We'll
do it We'll try to get it right right
this time. Belief growing that Iran
might false flag Al-Aqsa. Arab states
been feckless so far. What would the
consequences be?
False flag the in what kind of attack?
>> I think Do you mean the mosque or
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, that's what I was thinking. Okay.
So, Iran would do that to make it look
like Israel did it? I mean, I hate I
hate having to Guys, be you know, more
details, please, [laughter] cuz it
helps. Cuz we are in real time here.
Don't make us guess what you're trying
to say. I think that's what they're
saying, though.
Right. Um I mean, you can see that stuff
coming in from hundreds of miles away.
Oh, good point.
Yeah, that wouldn't happen. It wouldn't
be a very good false flag. Yeah, not to
mention, I mean, I I think it would be
it's just the idea of it would make the
Iranians sick, right? They just would
like, we can't do we can't do that.
Um Yeah, no.
>> Nikuprโคจิ, but they just wouldn't I
just don't think they would.
>> It's such a holy site. I You don't want
to destroy your own holy sites, even if
you think it might be a successful false
flag. Yeah, Nikuprโคจิ, thanks for the
five uh bucks. Hello everyone, quick
question, out of topic. John, how do you
survive without your stomach? I always
thought it was essential. Pardon, John.
Oh, it's it's harder than I thought it
was going to be.
Um
to tell you the truth, I throw up a lot,
which is not good, and the doctor is
like, you should have come back here as
soon as you started throwing up. I said,
I thought it was normal.
So, I've had two surgeries to clean out
scar tissue,
and um
but listen, the bottom line is,
I would rather be skinny and nauseous
than fat and sated. And my diabetes is
totally under control now. So, it
worked. I just can't enjoy food anymore.
Um yeah, I mean, a lot of people have
made that trade-off. Um
uh Matthew, uh hey, I'm from Brazil and
thanks for the 10 uh Brazilian reals. Uh
with Congress claiming we we host secret
Chinese bases and Trump labeling our
criminal groups as terrorists, could
Brazil be a target for intervention?
We have elections this year.
You know, I'm going to say no because
for a couple of reasons. Number one,
Brazil's an ally. Mm. Number two, it's
gigantic.
>> It's too big.
>> with a lot a lot of people.
And um
I mean, we can't fight in good weather.
>> as the continental United States.
>> It is. And and we can't fight on in you
know, in good weather on flat land, let
alone in the Amazon.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, with with 40-ft with 40-ft
anacondas and [__]
>> Yeah, and anacondas and panthers and
yes, piranhas. Yeah, we're not going to
do it.
>> No, it's impossible. You know, yeah.
Um
>> [laughter]
>> Super Talfa 1999, thank you so much.
John, given your knowledge on Saddam,
could you share any info about the Talfa
Talfa tribe in Iraq? I'm a
Jordanian-American Talfa and I want to
learn about where my tribe comes from or
where my direction.
Wow, that's cool. Well, the Talfa tribe
was extremely important in Saddam
Hussein's uh time. His father was
uh Khairallah Talfa.
Uh they were based in well, specifically
in the in the village of Al-Awja
in uh in Tikrit, northern Iraq not in
north-central Iraq.
Fierce fighters.
Uh proud large tribe.
That's That's something Listen, Saddam
and his wacky family aside, that is a
very proud
uh tribe to be
to be a part of. Congratulations. You
know, I love this kind of thing. I
Nobody knew these tribes like I did. And
one time I gave a briefing to the Deputy
Secretary of Commerce.
He wanted this briefing on tribes and I
went out there with a with a map of
Iran-Iraq. Well, actually it was just
like Iraq and the Arabian Peninsula. And
I was there for hours just talking about
tribes. And before I could even get back
to the building,
the Deputy Secretary called the Deputy
Director of the CIA for intelligence to
say that I had given him the most
detailed briefing he had ever had in his
life.
And he said, "Now, that's an expert."
I love that stuff cuz I love studying my
own family.
You know?
So, I congratulations on being a member
of the Tolfa tribe. That's wonderful.
Maria Vagand, thanks for the $3. That's
just the three Thank you for the $3.
So, then thanks for another generous
$19.99 contribution.
>> you so much.
>> Good morning, gents. The fraud is in
Minnesota. It was terrible and Fox News
played it over and over, but another
podcaster found fraud in Lakewood, New
Jersey with the Hasidic Jews doing the
same thing. It's been crickets on the
other side.
>> Oh, I'm I'm shocked. Shocked, I say.
>> [laughter]
>> The you know, the thing about about the
Orthodox Jews as a community
is they have this institutionalized
policy of
cheating welfare.
You'll You'll find people with eight,
10, 12 kids. They're all on welfare.
And that's why they have so many kids.
Because why would they work when they
can just study the Torah all day long
and make you and you and me pay for
their
That's what they do in Israel, right?
That's how they They do in Israel? Which
we said they don't work. They don't They
don't join the armed forces.
No.
Uh
although not joining the armed forces
when you're an Israeli is a point of
honor as far as I'm concerned.
>> True. There you go. Keith Fellers, BB is
Is BB still couch surfing?
I think so.
I You know, he was in Germany a week
ago. I heard day before yesterday he was
in Cyprus. He's been silent. So, he's
hiding out somewhere and I don't think
it's in Israel. N2100, what happens when
the world stops trading in the US
dollar?
Yeah, the economy goes into a tailspin.
In all seriousness, this is something
that I think is a is a long-term like a
big long term fear of every presidential
administration.
As soon as countries start start buying
and selling oil in a currency other than
the dollar on a regular basis, we're in
deep trouble.
John, how was being Ray wants to know
how it's being on Scotty's new show?
It was fun. Um
It was short. We It was also It wasn't
just Scotty Nell Hughes. It was her
daughter and it was Ben Swan's son.
They're both
uh journalism students.
And it was kind of a cute premise. It
was um
It was
why did I finally blow up in fame among
Gen Z when I'm in my 60s?
That's That's a I'm glad someone did
that.
>> [laughter]
>> It was fun. That's worth doing. Um DC,
and this brings us to our Maybe we
should talk about BART. DC 8828, San
Francisco also has the worst homeless
crisis per capita in the nation, and
that's not new at all. John, let's talk
about BART if you're if you're Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, I lived I used to
commute on BART. Um I lived there for uh
in San Franci- I lived in Berkeley, and
I used to commute into the city of San
Francisco every morning. Um and this was
in the uh mid-90s. And BART is an iconic
uh mass transit system that dates It was
They started in 1972. At the time, there
was basically mass transit was a
disaster in the United States, and
nobody was building new systems at all.
Um BART was along with the DC Metro was
like the two big systems that were like
we're going to start We're going to get
serious about mass transit. We're going
to do it again, right? The energy crisis
really drove it. And
And anyway, it spread throughout. And um
it's it's So, now basically it's kind of
like that I don't I For people who
aren't familiar with San Francisco, I
kind of want to explain. So in the city
you have the Muni system, right? Which
is basically street cars
>> That's right. and uh that go underground
sometimes and that are out on the street
at other times. Not to be confused with
the classic sort of tourist street cars.
And then there's a bus trolley system.
Um that's sort of and then uh BART is
more like regional transit. So in New
York that would be something like LI the
Long Island Railroad, the Metro-North.
Um it's it's more like the system they
have Marta in Atlanta where it goes out
into the suburbs or DC DC Metro
goes out into [clears throat] the
suburbs. Anyway, the point is
um it is a a kind of a sketchy system. I
mean it's like there's not a lot of
security. Doesn't It feels like, you
know, people see people smoke crack on
the trains and stuff. Um
it's also very expensive. Like if you
wanted to take uh a BART from SFO to
like say the northern San Francisco Bay
Area, it could easily be 14, 15 bucks
one way. Um and so, you know, as opposed
to like here in New York City
>> where it's a flat fare, which is an
effort to, you know, basically make the
system equitable for people who are poor
and live out in the sticks. Um you can
take the train from the Bronx to Far
Rockaway, Queens for, you know, a flat
subway fare, which is like, I don't
know, three bucks these days.
>> Yeah, three I think it's three bucks.
Yep. So
anyway, I don't I I take it, but I don't
know how much it is cuz I'm paying with
my phone, right? So
anyway, uh it's sort of so I guess here
basically what's they're they're uh the
BART administrators never recovered from
the pandemic. Uh they basically a
ridership is less than 50% of what it
was in 2020. It's never coming back
because of work at home, especially in,
you know, a tech city where big tech is.
So basically they're going to start um
they're they have a $400 million a year
annual loss.
They're asking for a new sales tax to be
approved by the Bay Area residents, but
it doesn't look likely to pass
cuz they you know they the San
Franciscans seem to not really believe
the
the supervisors of BART. So they're
thinking of cutting back the trains,
charging more for the fare, parking more
for parking, no more trains after 9:00
p.m. instead of 12:00 midnight. A laying
off a quarter of all BART workers,
closing 15 stations, all of which of
course will reduce ridership even more.
That's a doom loop, right?
It's a doom loop.
It's It's sort of like what we've seen
in newspaper right? You
charge more and more for less and less
and you know people leave faster and
faster.
It's literally possible that by the end
of 2027
you might be looking at the shutdown of
a major mass transit system
do that billions of dollars by the way a
lot of federal dollars were invested
into.
I mean what does this say about the
state of the nation? You know we were
talking yesterday Ted about defense
spending.
And and here it is. This is exactly the
problem
excuse me the problem with spending a
trillion dollars a year
on defense.
When
the the mass transit systems of the
greatest country in the in the world are
circling the drain.
Why is it so difficult to get from one
side of Los Angeles to the other?
Why does it take hours and hours
to go from one side of Los Angeles to
the other? It shouldn't. And there's a
tiny subway system it goes about that
far.
It's a full of homeless people sleeping
on
it.
Yep. It's gross. It's gross. You can see
the potential because it the you know,
insofar as it goes, if you ever find it
convenient I have taken it and it's
like, "Wow, this is really fast. If this
went all over, this would be great, you
know?" Yeah. But it doesn't.
Um yeah, and at least at least they're
they're they're building there. Um I So,
I mean, what's going to happen here? I
mean, do you think it would wake
Americans up if like a BART were to shut
down or just people who don't live in
San Francisco or work in San Francisco
just wouldn't care?
I think that nobody outside of San
Francisco would care because Republicans
for so long
have used San Francisco as a punching
bag that Remember there's even an app
that the Republicans put out where where
it had a map of San Francisco and it
would show you where human feces were on
the street. Yeah. Do you remember that?
I do remember that. Look, they're not
They weren't wrong. I was Last time the
cartoonist convention was in in in San
Fran, which is only a few years ago, I
was on the Muni
and some guy pulled his pants down and
took a [__] on the bus on a moving bus.
I'm a New Yorker, okay? I don't gross
out easy.
It's like
and people were just like, "Woah,
whatever." You know, nobody got off. You
know, people did barely even moved out
of the way to the other side of the car.
I said, "This place is degenerate." Um
you know, I think people won't care, but
it is But it is shameful and uh
I don't know. I mean, to me, San
Francisco also has a structural
problem in in its governance, which is
that so much of the tax base is now down
the peninsula, uh you know, in Mountain
View at like these big companies like
Google and Apple. They're not sharing
the wealth.
Right. So, Palo Alto and Menlo Park and
those municipalities get the money. I
mean, it'd probably be wise if San There
was some kind of tax sharing um thing
cuz basically it's very strange. I mean
in the old days when you and I were kids
people lived in the suburbs and commuted
downtown to work. Yes.
>> Here in San Francisco
the kids the the millennials they live
in San Francisco cuz it's fun and cool
and Palo Alto is boring and then they
commute out to Palo Alto or whatever
then they go back and it's it's totally
opposite but that means they're paying
their you know the the companies they
work at are down the peninsula.
Yes.
It's right. It's backwards.
It's very weird.
>> And you know and then later urban
planning called for
called for like nodes to be built. So
you build all an office building in the
middle of nowhere but then you build
housing and shopping around it. New
urbanism. Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
That is I mean I've seen it work in some
places. I like San Francisco a lot. I
really do.
And I could live there if it didn't have
these
the problem of homelessness and people
[__] everywhere and you know stuff
like that.
It's an amazing city. It is. I really
blame the people though. They don't
stand up for themselves. They don't. Two
quick stories. One time I'm walking down
the street and I see someone like
throw their litter down on the ground
like it's like 5 ft away from a trash
can and I'm like hey dude the trash
can's right there. Before he can tell me
to piss off this other guy who's not
even involved
shoves me and goes hey man he has his
reasons. And I'm like [__] off. What?
>> that's sort of like the San Francisco
way like if someone's [__] around in
traffic like the light turns green they
don't go and you give them a little boop
a little beep um other people will get
mad at you for honking. There's no self
policing in the city of San Francisco.
It's all the the culture is everybody
leave everybody alone everybody's cool
and then so you know and I was talking
one time on a stuck BART. I was like,
"Does this happen all the time?" The
guys are, "Yeah, every day." I go, "You
guys don't raise hell? You guys don't go
out down to the transit authority and
scream at them?"
No, what can you do? I'm like, "Go down
to the transit authority and scream at
them. New Yorkers do."
I remember moving to New York
in 2000
and
our first night there, my wife and I
went for a walk and just at the end of
the walk, she stepped in a pile of [__]
And she said, "Oh, no, I stepped in dog
shit." And I said, "You hope."
>> [laughter]
>> True.
Benjamin Garvin 700 uh
uh okay okay, I I am having such a hard
time keeping track of all this. Okay. Um
Okay, here we go. Um Zizi, thank you
very much for the 29.99 Australian
dollars. Much appreciated. Um okay.
Benjamin, love the show. Iran has over
800 lb of 60% enriched uranium, which is
well beyond needed for nuclear power. Is
this for negotiation leverage? How did
the former Ayatollahs feel about nukes?
Thanks.
Well, there was a formal fatwa that uh
that Ayatollah Khamenei uh had issued
what, 20-something years ago, forbidding
Iran from developing a nuclear weapon.
And two That's never reported in
American news.
>> Never reported.
>> Ever. Two national intelligence
estimates concluding that the Iranians
did not have a nuclear weapons program
and were not seeking nuclear weapons.
Nor long-range inter- intercontinental
ballistic missiles.
The missiles that the Iranians have
are barely able to reach like the
easternmost Greek islands. That's it.
That's as far as they go.
Um
what
Michael, what aspect do you guys think
plays a more important role in shaping
personality? Race, ethnicity, or
religious affiliation?
Such an interesting question. I'd have
to go with religious affiliation for
personality.
I think probably, yeah.
Um cuz I mean
>> all all of them in a way, but yeah, I
think I would have to agree with you.
Religious [snorts]
affiliation.
Nate Holden has a question for you,
John. Are you still planning to speak at
the University of Pittsburgh this week?
Pretty sure that you said it would be
today, but it looks like you're home.
Tomorrow.
Um
I'm going to
I'm going to do it by Zoom.
Because
>> [laughter]
>> Listen, I'm happy to I'm happy to do a
speech for 500 bucks for a friend,
right?
But
I signed last week with a Creative
Artists Agency, CAA.
And they said from now on you speak for
25,000 plus business class expenses.
Good for them.
>> Everybody else the answer's no. I said,
"Yeah, but a buddy of mine at Pitt." And
he's like they said, "Okay, do it for
your buddy, but it's 25,000 now. It's
not 500." And so they've already booked
me a bunch of speeches at 25,000. So I
told my friend, "Listen, I'm not going
to
block off an entire day and drive all
the way to Pittsburgh for $500. So I'm
going to do it on Zoom."
Okay.
>> [snorts]
>> Fair. TS Wolf, thanks for the dollar.
Saw yesterday that Hezbollah has sent
sent the Radwan fighters into southern
Lebanon. Yeah. John, would you mind
telling people about the Radwan fighters
because I know at least I had no idea
how lethal they are.
The Radwan fighters
were created in 2006.
And they are of course a part of
Hezbollah's military wing, but they are
specifically
trained to
cross the border and infiltrate
um Israeli settlements in northern
Israel
to kill people.
So, you know, Hezbollah is lethal. It's
always been lethal. These guys are like
extra lethal. They're They're very well
trained. They're well armed. They're
perfectly happy to do [snorts] suicide
uh attacks just so long as they can take
out settlers. And now they've been
activated.
And I was surprised frankly that they
hadn't been activated earlier.
Donors, um thanks for the $4.99. Uh
question for both of us, would you
support Jon Stewart for president? No.
No.
John, you want to say why? No, no, no.
Yeah, he's a Zionist and uh he's very
DNC mainstream Democrat.
I I would compare him very much to
Rachel Maddow who to whom I wouldn't
give the time of the day. So, no, not
interested.
>> Agreed with that. Not to mention, um you
know,
yeah, John never has once had a real
leftist when he had his show uh as a as
a guest ever ever ever ever.
>> Never. Um so, yeah. Ezra PR, thanks for
the five bucks. My mistake, I meant
Israel doing a false flag on Al Aqsa and
then blame Iran. Coffee hadn't hit yet.
I think we figured that out.
>> Yeah,
I know. I can't imagine them blowing up
the third holiest site in Islam just to
point the finger at the Israelis.
Cuz the Israelis are probably planning
to blow it up anyway.
>> [snorts]
>> Oh, the yeah, no, for sure.
>> they're talking about constructing the
third temple. You got to blow up Al Aqsa
to do it. Yep, that's right. Uh Brady
Okerlund, thanks for the $19.99. Uh hey
guys, if US naval escorts are too
escalatory,
but I wouldn't say they're escalatory. I
just say that they become big fat juicy
targets for the Iranians.
But leaving Hormuz closed risks
recession. What specific alternative
would you use to reopen it without
rewarding Iran's mining and threats?
Good luck with the pardon. I don't think
there's anything on God's green earth
the US can do about it. I mean, it's
it's their neighborhood. They've got
they they can button it up tight, you
know, like a
like a I don't know, something
they but they it's there's nothing we
can do. No, what what Reagan did was
he sent minesweepers and escort ships.
And so it was kind of a, you know,
face-off. And then it and then it
passed. But Ted, you're right. If if
they want to shut it down, there's
practically nothing that we can do.
Yeah, and people might say, "Well,
what's the difference?" Right? Well, the
difference was
in Reagan's time, Iran wasn't looking
for a war with the United States.
But we're already at war.
You know, this is the second time in a
year the Iranians think that we're out
to destroy them and turn them into a
vassal state, which they have good
reason to think because that's what the
president of the United States is
telling them repeatedly every hour on
social media. So, like of course, you
know, there's
it's a different scenario. I mean, the
US can
the US can try to I mean, I don't even
know how many vessels would even accept
the escort, right? I mean, just think
about the value,
you know, which can exceed 500 million
dollars worth of
oil can be on an oil tanker, right?
>> Yes. And so, just think, you know, one
thing turns that into a bomb, one little
drone. And I mean, you know, if you own
that oil, if you're that company, or if
you're like Maersk with, you know, some
giant shipping contain
you know, shipping container ship,
you're not you're not going to, you
know, you're not going to risk that.
Like, "Oh, well, don't worry, Donald
Trump's got your back." Oh, yeah, that
makes me feel good. You're You're to sit
tight until things are okay.
Things are not okay.
No, things are not okay. Agreed. John
Templar wants to know, thanks for the
$4.99, is Iran's missile capability
showing signs of failure or slowing
down?
I don't think it is yet, but that's
probably coming. I'll tell you, so long
as regional countries are
are living in fear of these missiles,
they're serving their purpose. I'm in
touch daily with a friend of mine
in Cyprus. She's a kind of a prominent
podcaster, and she gives me these daily
updates. And Cypriots are panicked.
Right? So, there have been three
launches. Two two drones, two suicide
drones, and a missile. They've all three
been intercepted. They were probably
headed for the British bases,
but
Cypriots are terrified.
We're going to get to a point where
they will have used
most or all of their missiles. And then
either the Russians and Chinese are
going to have to resupply them or
they're going to have to just kind of
give up, but
so far
>> the Russians can resupply directly,
right? Across the land.
>> That's right. Um so, yeah.
Uh how would the Chinese do it though?
The Chinese would have to go through
Central Asia? How would they do Yeah,
they'd probably have to go through
Central Asia, and I'm not sure
that they could get permission to do it.
Well, the Turkmen have a Turkmenistan
has a official policy of neutrality.
Um so, I can't imagine them allowing uh
weapons to transit across their country.
Um the Uzbeks are corrupt enough that
they might let it go.
You know, you'd only have to go China to
Kazakhstan to Uzbekistan to Iran. You'd
only have to get it through
I don't know. The Kazakhs would be the
hard part, I think, cuz they're they're
trying to run a tight ship. Some
hilarious breaking news, I mean, uh uh
duh, Iran can is said it will not be
able to participate in the World Cup due
to the current hostilities.
>> [gasps]
>> Shocking.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh 20 Mark So, uh thanks for the 1999.
Hey guys, love the show.
When will it ever be enough for Israel?
Do they want to occupy the Middle East?
What happens with this 50 to 100 years
from now?
Oh, it Chad, do you remember the David
Bowie ad for MTV? Too much is never
enough.
Yeah.
I do.
That's
Too much is never enough for the
Israelis.
>> There's no limit for the Israelis.
None.
>> If 50 to 100 years from now, I honestly
don't have a clue. Uh I mean, care to
care to guess?
I I it's it's got to be indefinite. I
mean, they they won't stop.
And they won't
they won't listen to reason, and we're
not ballsy enough to tell them to stop.
So, no, I I I can't imagine
anything being enough for the Israelis.
Gonzo Lives Matter, thanks for the 999.
As As a legal immigrant, I was very sad
with your statements yesterday. I
followed all the rules because it's the
law, and today I'm being seen as the
same because of problems caused by
illegal immigration. It hurts us all.
I I think we we agree with that, right?
I'm
Yeah. What did What did we say that was?
Um I I think basically just sort of the
sense that uh immigration
you know, takes away American jobs, and
you know, we should I mean, look, if you
followed the rules,
no one you no one has any right to
criticize you.
None. Zero.
Uh
Adams, uh thanks for the uh Emirati the
10 Emirati uh dirhams.
Any chance that Bibi could taken out by
Iran?
I think so.
You know, it's possible. I'm not if he's
hiding in Germany, but it's it's
possible.
We we saw, you know, in the 12-day war
back in October, whenever it was.
Um
we saw more than a half a dozen drones
get through the the Iron Dome.
If
if Iran is able to flood Israeli
airspace with drones,
there aren't enough missiles in the Iron
Dome to protect
everything
everywhere all the time to, you know,
make a pun.
Um
so yeah, it's possible.
Not likely, but possible.
Shahinnajaficity999,
John, in your Q&A, you said that your
partner is Persian. Love that. What's it
like dating a Persian at this time? And
what are your three favorite Persian
dishes?
Don't tell anybody,
>> [laughter]
>> but I don't really like Persian food.
Um
in all seriousness,
she cries a lot.
And it's because like her life every day
is is reports of death and destruction.
And she she tries to talk to her friends
and her family in Iran and around the
world, and their stories are stories of
death and destruction every day.
Um she she usually goes to Iran once or
twice a year. She can't do that. Um
people are stuck there. People she cares
about are stuck there. And you know,
there's
always a risk of the Israelis bombing an
apartment building, which they're doing
in her neighborhood. Her her
uh, condo that she owns and and where
her cousin lives, um,
has not been hit, but the neighborhood
has been hit.
And, um,
yeah, there's there's no good that's
going to come out of this at all. None.
Just death.
I mean, let me push back on that a
little bit. I mean, could if Iran were
to really bloody the Israelis and or the
Americans noses to the point where we
[__] off for a while and left them
alone, wouldn't that be a good outcome?
That would be a good outcome, and it
would allow the Iranians to reassess and
re-evaluate their own policy. Listen, if
you are an Iranian leader,
and you survive this,
you would be a fool
to not
initiate a nuclear weapons program.
You would have to make a nuclear bomb to
protect yourself from the next time the
Americans and the Israelis decide to
bomb you and invade you.
Um,
at score, uh, John, I was wondering if
you Thanks for the 999. I was wondering
if you'd seen the video of George
Galloway talking about how Israel looks
like Gaza now and how the media is lying
about the death count of Americans. Uh,
hoping you get that pardon. Look, the
death count of the Americans is
something that clearly the
administration is not being straight
with us about. The way that the reports
are trickling out in like very like
unknown like first we get numbers, we
don't even know where these incidents
happened. Suddenly the numbers spike
from six to seven to 140, not deaths,
but you know, injuries. Um, you know, I
mean, we're clearly not being They're
not playing it straight with us. They're
not playing it straight with us. And and
I will say, too, that I was offended
that when Donald Trump met
the returning bodies of the servicemen
who have died,
he never took off his baseball cap.
That's his formal baseball cap
for formal occasions.
>> The Republicans would have lost their
[__] if Joe Biden or Barack Obama or
Bill Clinton had done something similar.
True.
>> The Republicans lost their [__] once
because Barack Obama wore a brown suit.
Did you see what
>> Fox? Did you see what Fox News did? Fox
News aired old footage from another
ceremony where he had a bare head and no
hat in it to to illustrate uh to pretend
that that's, you know, basically they
presented it like here he is at the um
at the at the dignified transfer.
And it's like and then they got caught
out and they had to admit, but of course
they admitted on like Fox and Friends at
like, you know, 6:00 in the morning on a
Saturday
when, you know, nobody's watching.
Pretty sad. Um
um thanks very much for the 100 Saudi
Riyals. Uh Thank you. Shia Shia Muslims
in Persia don't believe that Al-Aqsa is
in Palestine. They think Al-Aqsa is
located above in the sky. Yeah, they do.
So, a false flag operation is possible
on both sides for the Israelis and the
Iranians.
Mhm.
Yeah, that's true, actually.
That's a good point.
So, okay. Um
tw- uh thanks for the 999 from uh 20
Marco uh Marco. I'm asked about 50 to
100 years from now because I'm a young
man. All I want is for my children to
prosper. How do they do so
when officials say they elect um
I
I I can't can't figure out that word. Uh
too misspelled. Sir I don't know. Uh
servants or something no beneficial
purpose. Honestly, John, I think that
like the biggest problem that people are
going to have 50 years from now is going
to be environmental. Uh it's, you know,
the there's already predictions that
human civilization is going to start to
collapse by the year 2050. I think the
environmental situation is what people
should be focused on.
Ted, may I jump in real quick? Please.
One minute. Young Young Courthouse,
thank you for the $5. This is so
wonderful.
Young Courthouse says, "Hey John,
congrats on the Sheabutter. Also,
John McLaughlin is a professor at my
school.
Anything cheeky I should say to him?
John McLaughlin is the former deputy
director of the CIA under George Tenet.
And he was one of the godfathers of the
torture program.
Um
yeah.
Uh
John McLaughlin is an accomplished
magician. It's it's a hobby that he's
had since his childhood, and he's
he's just great at sleight of hand.
Maybe you can ask him if he can
do some kind of magic trick to
make his co-creation of the torture
program disappear."
Funny. Uh John, we have a few uh
questions we really have to get to
before we close out. Uh Tangent, thanks
for the 20. Uh if Iran did take out
Bibi, what do you think the Israeli
United States would do? Who is second
command after him?
Wow, that's a good question. Nobody that
anyone knows of.
There would be a dozen guys scrapping it
out to take over, you know, control of
Likud.
But he's not a Likud member. And Likud
is the
is the largest part of the block.
Wouldn't they have to have a snap
election?
I think they probably would have to.
Yeah. Yeah. So, uh yeah, I mean,
obviously, you know, life goes on.
Uh it's not a I don't think it's just a
Bibi thing at this point. Uh it's an
Israel thing. Um
uh also, uh thanks for the buck from Sir
Bikes-A-Lot. If you want to interview
any new urbanist or transit expert, I
recommend Jarrett Walker, author of
Human Transit, and Charles Marohn of
Strong Towns. Thanks for that. Sir
Bike-a-Lot, also thanks for the two
bucks. The best transit system that I've
ever ridden is the VIA in San Antonio.
Second best is UTA in Salt Lake. I like
the UTA. If you're not driving your car,
then you're not burning gasoline and
Chevron isn't making uh SA uh dollars
off you. Uh yeah, I mean I'm trying Best
transit system in the country. Um
I'm going to have to say it's New York
City cuz it's the only city in the
country that you can truly live a
high-quality life and not own a car.
>> Not own a car. I would agree with that.
Washington's pretty
clean, modern, and sophisticated. It
doesn't go everywhere everywhere.
Um
but it goes to Dallas Airport now,
which, you know, saves me 75 bucks every
time I need to do it.
>> Yeah, Dallas Airport is like a good hour
drive west of DC. Uh-huh. I mean it's I
couldn't believe how far it was the
first time I flew in there.
Um
>> Crazy. Yeah, it's just nuts. Um so,
let's see. Um
I guess we do have a little time for a
few more. Let's see.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh is Russia Matina now Russia's taking
advantage of the war and expanding to
the Balkans?
I haven't heard that. Yeah, yeah, I
hadn't heard that either. Um from an
intelligence perspective, John. Oh, I
don't know if we have time for this. Uh
we have 30 seconds. Um how would the CIA
and the Pentagon react if the UK gave US
forces 24 hours to leave its bases? If
Germany did the same, would Washington
see it as a crisis in NATO?
Yeah, they would it would never happen,
but if it were to happen, yeah, it would
be the end of NATO.
Sure.
Uh someone's taking issue with my idea
that John never had real leftists on his
show is [__] Really? Name one.
Email me. roll.com/contact.
Okay.
Uh every Thanks everyone for joining us.
You've been watching The Program with
Ted Rall and John Kiriakou. We'll be
back tomorrow, Thursday, March 12th at
9:00 a.m. Eastern Time. Thanks uh please
like, follow, and share the show. John,
see you tomorrow and
everybody else, I'm going to please
stick around for the TMI show with
myself and Manila Chan except Robbie
Manila's out today. Robbie will be
filling in.
See y'all.
>> [music]